The story of the search for the beginning of time.
Hawking is a drama, tv movie film directed by Philip Martin.
The story of Professor Stephen Hawking's early years.
It is 1963, and our young cosmologist celebrates his 21st birthday.
At the party is a new friend, Jane Wilde - there is a
strong attraction between the two.
Jane is intrigued by Stephen's talk of stars and the Universe.
But she realises that there is something very wrong when Stephen
suddenly finds that he is unable to stand up.
Stephen Hawking, played by Benedict Cumberbatch.
Sir Fred Hoyle, played by Peter Firth.
Roger Penrose, played by Tom Ward.
Jane Wilde, played by Lisa Dillon.
Dennis Sciama, played by John Sessions.
Isobel Hawking, played by Phoebe Nicholls.
Hawking is a 2004 biographical drama television film directed
by Philip Martin and written by Peter Moffat.
Starring Benedict Cumberbatch, it chronicles Stephen Hawking's early years as a PhD student at the University of
Cambridge, following his search for the beginning of time, and his struggle against motor neurons disease.
It premiered in the UK in April 2004.
The film received positive reviews, with critics particularly
lauding Cumberbatch's performance as Hawking.
It received two British Academy Television Awards nominations:
Best Single Drama and Best Actor (Cumberbatch).
Cumberbatch won the Golden Nymph for Best Performance
by an Actor in a TV Film or Miniseries.
Cumberbatch's portrayal of Hawking was the first portrayal
of the physicist on screen not by himself.
The film explores themes of physics, biography, scientist, 1960s, phd thesis.
The tone is emotional.